<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Electric]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Health Electric]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 11:25:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/pemf/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/dadbc726-5e9a-4709-840b-3536c212137f.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/healing-up-my-bones-great/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6c8df2c3-eab5-40a9-8710-95f0bffa458f</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 09:51:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8af3be1c-2334-4b5b-9a6b-ee968aa02602.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/i-just-feel-energized/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">83d14369-2416-4f5a-8825-baf3deafa44a</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 09:50:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/10c5437f-b759-4d0a-9a69-633d3837fe78.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/my-spine-is-doing-great-after-my-pmf-session/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9ed89358-6116-4775-bf2a-528875f752e4</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 09:48:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USES of PEMF]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>USES of PEMF</h1><p>An old fracture with nonunion of the fracture fragments. In 1974 it was demonstrated that a pulsed magnetic field applied across the site of a bone fracture can accelerate the healing process (Bassett et al., 1974). The mechanism of osteogenesis is not clear; however, the use of PEMF therapy as an adjuvant therapy for delayed- and non-union fractures was supported by empirical evidence collected through clinical studies.[7][8] While PEMF therapy may offer some benefit in the treatment of fractures, the evidence is inconclusive and is insufficient to inform current clinical practice.[9] Although electricity’s potential to aid bone healing was reported as early as 1841, it was not until the mid-1950s that scientists seriously studied the subject. Fukada’s and Yasuda’s discovery of the electric potential of bone provided evidence of electricity’s effect in promoting osteogenesis (bone growth), particularly in long bone non-unions.[10] During the 1970s, Bassett and his team introduced a new approach for the treatment of delayed fractures, a technique that employed a very specific biphasic low frequency signal [11][12][13][14] to be applied for non-union/delayed fractures. The use of electrical stimulation in the lumbosacral region was first attempted by Alan Dwyer of Australia. In 1974, he reported successful initiation of graft incorporation in 11 of 12 fusion patients. Since that time, electrical stimulation has been shown to significantly increase the probability of bony arthrodesis in spinal fusions.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/uses-of-pemf/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">eacad370-acc4-41c1-9754-b91acd6cb34f</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 09:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[History of PEMF]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>History of PEMF</h1><p>asd</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/history-of-pemf/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">89c60429-7747-4a04-9ef6-8fa7a2652b26</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 09:35:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is PEMF?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What is PEMF?</h1><p>Pulsed electromagnetic field therapy (PEMFT), also called pulsed magnetic therapy, pulse magnetotherapy, or PEMF, is a reparative technique most commonly used in the field of orthopedics for the treatment of non-union fractures, failed fusions, congenital pseudarthrosis and depression.[1] In the case of bone healing, PEMF uses directed pulsed magnetic fields through injured tissue. This is believed to stimulate cellular repair. The FDA has approved several such stimulation devices. These devices provide a complementary solution that may aid in bone repair.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bd96be8d-3ca1-4d38-b60e-edff0f14dd4a.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/pemf/what-is-pemf/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3ce63010-7ceb-4178-9468-85f56d3cb169</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 09:33:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>